<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Code52</title>
  <link href="http://www.Code52.org/"/>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://www.Code52.org/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>2011-12-29T23:45:27+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.Code52.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Code52 Team</name>
    <email>Code52@Code52.org</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <id>http://www.Code52.org//downmarker</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.Code52.org//downmarker.html"/>
    <title>Week 1: Downmarker WPF</title>
    <updated>2012-01-02T00:00:00+11:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Code52 Team</name>
      <uri>http://www.Code52.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our first run out of the gate is a project that a few people have taken a stab at in the past, and will help us blog easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/wcoenen/downmarker&quot;&gt;Downmarker&lt;/a&gt; project is an editor for  &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; a widely used syntax for formatting plain text to convert to blogs, comments, and in other places like on &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to create a useably, stylish new version of the project utilising Microsoft's WPF technology to provide a fresh UI for creating files that we can use to create blog posts for this, and other blogs using Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be discussing this on our &lt;a href=&quot;http://talk.code52.org/discussions/projects/2-downmarker-wpf&quot;&gt;TenderApp discussions&lt;/a&gt;  but you can also ping us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/code_52&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to volunteer or have a word with us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://jabbr.net/#/rooms/code52&quot;&gt;Jabbr&lt;/a&gt; if we're around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As will be our usual scenario - we'll be dedicating this week to kickstarting this project, which may of course go on for more than a week, but our aim is to try to get what we can sorted and organised, and hopefully coded this week to start momentum on this as a full tool in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many hands make light work we hope you'll put your hand up to participate on the above methods, we're more than happy for you to do as much as you're willing to do to help us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our key goals is to give back to the community and all the source will be under an open source license and available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Code52/DownmarkerWPF&quot;&gt;our Github repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'll review our progress in next week's post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also submit or vote on what the next project will be at our &lt;a href=&quot;http://code52.uservoice.com/&quot;&gt;UserVoice&lt;/a&gt; site - we're happy to take any ideas for apps, tools, plugins or anything else that you think would be helpful and would like to crowdsource as an Open Source project :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-- Code52 team&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://www.Code52.org//introduction</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.Code52.org//introduction.html"/>
    <title>Introducing code52</title>
    <updated>2011-12-31T00:00:00+11:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Code52 Team</name>
      <uri>http://www.Code52.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This all started with a simple premise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&quot;A new coding project every week&quot;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madness! I was hooked and &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/gobsmacked&quot;&gt;gobsmacked&lt;/a&gt; at the same time. I had so many questions, and as we discussed it we started to come to something resembling an agreement. We want to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;introduce developers to open-source projects and help them learn the ropes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;foster a community which encouraged contributions across a range of technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work on projects which the community (i.e. YOU) want to improve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt; Of course, that doesn't get away from the original question I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&quot;Why a week?&quot;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; A week isn't a long time - or it may be, depending on your perspective. This is still a somewhat contentious point within the group, but a week suits me because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shorter timelines encourage achievable goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shorter timelines reduce the incentive to procrastinate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more variety of projects to work on over a period of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with good organisation, each week should be productive out of the gate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;&quot;What's next?&quot;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; But there are some things we need to address first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do we determine which projects to work on?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do we organise each project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do we (as co-ordinators) deal with the skill gap between experienced and junior developers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt; We want to &lt;strong&gt;build fun stuff&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;give back&lt;/strong&gt; to the projects which have been useful to us, and potentially &lt;strong&gt;create a community&lt;/strong&gt; around this crazy idea.  So whatever your background - if you want to get involved and work with others in the developer community, we'd love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Do you have an project which suits this idea? &lt;a href=&quot;http://code52.uservoice.org&quot;&gt;Vote on it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Want to discuss your ideas and suggestions?  &lt;a href=&quot;http://code52.tenderapp.com&quot;&gt;Share it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Want to get in touch? Follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter/code_52&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
