<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
    <title>Code52</title>
    <link>http://www.Code52.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.Code52.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 21:12:09 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 21:12:09 +1100</lastBuildDate>

    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to code52</title>
      <link>http://www.Code52.org/introduction.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <author>code52@code52.org (Code52 Team)</author>
      <guid>http://www.Code52.org/introduction</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don't know which one of my co-conspirators came up with the idea, but it all started with a simple premise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;A new coding project every week&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madness! Surely it couldn't be possible. What would that even involve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had so many questions, but as we discussed it we started to come to something resembling an agreement. We wanted to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;introduce more developers to open-source projects and help them learn the ropes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;foster a community that encouraged contributions across a range of technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work on projects which the community want to improve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt; Of course, that doesn't get away from the original question I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Why a week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; A week isn't a long time - or it may be, depending on your perspective. This is still a somewhat contentious point within the group, but a week suits me because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shorter timelines encourage achievable goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shorter timelines reduce the incentive to procrastinate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more variety of projects to work on - something different each week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with good organisation, each week should be productive out of the gate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt; But there are some things we need to address first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;What next?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to work out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do we determine which projects to work on?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_revision_control&quot;&gt;DVCS&lt;/a&gt; is still a relatively new concept - how can we help getting new developers familiar with it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do we organise each project? We want to give value both to the project owners and the contributors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt; We want to &lt;strong&gt;build fun stuff&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;give back&lt;/strong&gt; to the projects who have helped us over the years, and &lt;strong&gt;create a community&lt;/strong&gt; around our crazy ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; So whatever your background and skillset, if you want to get involved and learn from others in the community, we'd love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; So drop in on our &lt;a href=&quot;http://code52.uservoice.org&quot;&gt;UserVoice&lt;/a&gt; channel and suggest or vote on projects, discuss your ideas and suggestions on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://code52.tenderapp.com&quot;&gt;TenderApp&lt;/a&gt; site, and follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/code52_org&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to hear more about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    

  </channel> 
</rss>